<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on hannah s kim</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on hannah s kim</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>thoughts on NaNoWriMo &#39;24</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/thoughts-on-nanowrimo-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/thoughts-on-nanowrimo-24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another November means another NaNoWriMo. To start, I want to say: spoiler alert! I’ve done it again. November 30, 2024 marks another 50k words down in my novel, which has now passed the 120k word mark.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Am I proud? Hell yeah. It was a really long process, and I didn’t write that much in the eleven months that passed between one NaNoWriMo to the next. That meant that I felt a little out of my element going in, but at least I had the foresight to at least open the doc before the first day so that I could reorient myself. What was I writing again? What chapter are we on? What’s supposed to happen next?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Another November means another NaNoWriMo. To start, I want to say: spoiler alert! I’ve done it again. November 30, 2024 marks another 50k words down in my novel, which has now passed the 120k word mark.</p>
<p>Am I proud? Hell yeah. It was a really long process, and I didn’t write that much in the eleven months that passed between one NaNoWriMo to the next. That meant that I felt a little out of my element going in, but at least I had the foresight to at least open the doc before the first day so that I could reorient myself. What was I writing again? What chapter are we on? What’s supposed to happen next?</p>
<p>Writer’s block is weird that way. I ended NaNoWriMo ‘23 at a weak point. I was in the middle of a transition, with no clear scene for me to work off of. It was a whole lot of character development that I needed to write but could not decide how to. There were scenes that needed to get done that I couldn’t get to, simply because I couldn’t figure out how to connect one scene to the next without feeling as though I was dragging myself through mud. So when I finished the month, it would be months before I could bring myself to open the doc again, and many months before I could write a few paragraphs, much less an entire <em>scene</em>.</p>
<p>So, I knew I had a challenge this year. And I’m a perfectionist. I hate leaving things undone, and I’ll painstakingly agonize over every word as I write until I’m at least somewhat satisfied with how the sentences flow and what the characters are saying. Does it fit their personality? Would they <em>actually</em> do this?</p>
<p>And that was the problem. Let’s be serious. I’m writing the first draft of a novel, and it’s the first time I’m writing something of this length in… ever. I have never written anything this long before. Do I logically think I could write a Pulitzer prize winner on the first draft? No, of course not. Does that stop me from trying? Also no.</p>
<p>It’s two very different things to recognize this fact about myself and to actually do something to fix it. I spent the few months leading up to this November anxiously trying to get myself into the headspace of a “first draft writer.” We’re allowed to skip entire scenes, leave comments to remind ourselves of what we need to work on later, and keep barreling on so we don’t lose steam. The entire point of a first draft is to make it <em>exist</em>, not to ship it out to publishers.</p>
<p>Realistically, it will take me another year to finish the first draft if I keep the pace I’ve been going at. And it will take me years to edit and to write a second draft. And even more years to write a third draft. Rinse and repeat. And from there, if I decide I want to publish, it will take me many more years.</p>
<p>That’s reality. And recognizing this made NaNoWriMo so much easier.</p>
<p>So I wrote a lot of “<!-- raw HTML omitted -->”’s this year. And left a lot of “BLANK”s when I didn’t want to stop and come up with a name for a new character or city. And when I say a lot, I mean a <em>lot.</em> There’s entire chunks of time (in story) that are missing, where I have mentally filled in the gaps of how the characters have developed in that time. And that’s okay. I will come back to it later, once I am done with this draft.</p>
<p>It’s frustrating to admit, but yeah, I made a lot of progress this year by <em>not</em> writing.</p>
<p><img src="/images/nnwm24.png" alt="the perfect progress line"></p>
<p>But isn’t that so satisfying?</p>
<p>I could write a whole novel (as scary as that is) about how I feel about NaNoWriMo as a program. I love it as a way to encourage myself to write, and their pretty graphs and awards do wonders to give me unimaginable amounts of motivation. But unfortunately, in the final few days of NaNoWriMo this year, I learned that the team is what they call “AI neutral.”</p>
<p>There’s a time and a place for AI. Like in cancer research. But in all honesty, I do not believe there are many other situations where AI is genuinely useful. Generative artwork? Absolutely not. Chat bots? Maybe I’m old fashioned, but I like Google just fine. And it’s not just that I think there are better alternatives. All things considering, AI is fantastically helpful sometimes, and I admit I do use it when I absolutely cannot find what I need on Google.</p>
<p>What I hate, though, is the “hidden” impact AI has on us. Stealing data from people, <em>especially</em> artists and creatives, to train their models without permission. Draining the environment of resources to power servers that run the models. The humans behind training data who are underpaid and not recognized. These things weigh heavily on me when I think of AI and whenever I see a piece of AI generated art.</p>
<p>So when I heard that NaNoWriMo is “AI neutral”, I could not help but finish this month with a sour taste in my mouth. As a creative community, NaNoWriMo was the last place I expected to be welcoming of AI works. It stings a little, of course, to have spent dozens of hours writing scene after scene, training myself to push past my too high standards, just to find that an AI generated work could do all that in a few hours, or maybe a day, with barely any human intervention.</p>
<p>What’s the point of that? “Writing” without emotion or human thought? What message could an AI come up with that isn’t an idea stolen from other writers? Was it Shakespeare that it trained off of, or maybe Agatha Christie? Or was it me? How many gallons of water did it require to generate 50k words? How much of that water are we getting back?</p>
<p>Anyways. Aside from doom spiraling about AI, I spent time thinking of what I wanted to do next year. I don’t think that I can, with a clear conscious, go back to using NaNoWriMo’s site. I have already found a few alternatives, including <a href="https://trackbear.app/">TrackBear</a>, which I’ve been using a little since November ended. And, of course, I’m a software engineer, so I have the means to create what I want to keep from NaNoWriMo myself.</p>
<p>So, when in November 2025, I am no longer a user on the NaNoWriMo site, know that this is the reason why.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>a reflection on NaNoWriMo ‘23</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/a-reflection-on-nanowrimo-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/a-reflection-on-nanowrimo-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For starters, this is my first blog post! I decided to start up blogging since 1. I enjoy writing, 2. I enjoy journaling, and 3. why not? The idea of having my thoughts, my words, and my personality out on the internet is simultaneously terrifying and humbling. Maybe, many years down the line, someone will stumble upon my little page on the internet and get to learn about who I am.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For starters, this is my first blog post! I decided to start up blogging since 1. I enjoy writing, 2. I enjoy journaling, and 3. why not? The idea of having my thoughts, my words, and my personality out on the internet is simultaneously terrifying and humbling. Maybe, many years down the line, someone will stumble upon my little page on the internet and get to learn about who I am.</p>
<p>Regardless, I wanted to spend my first blog post talking about NaNoWriMo! NaNoWriMo stands for National Novel Writing Month, and it happens every November. Writers, both recreational and professional, are encouraged to work on their novels for the entirety of November and write 50k words. It doesn’t really matter if you start a project from scratch or continue an existing one, but for me, I decided to start from the beginning.</p>
<p>I had a novel idea for the past little while, but I purposefully procrastinated on starting it until NaNoWriMo started so that I could fully encourage (re: force) myself to work on it. The website has a great portal for entering how many words you’ve written in a day (as well as how long it took, how you felt, etc, but I didn’t really keep track of that, since I tended to write throughout the entire day). I also made an effort to post on my Twitter about how much I was writing, so that I could keep myself accountable, but I also… stopped doing that.</p>
<p>I have always enjoyed writing since I was a kid – a lot of my earliest memories were of me writing my own picture books. Even when I hadn’t learned to write yet, I was narrating to my dad what I wanted him to write, and I would fill the empty spaces with illustrations. Back then, before I had ready access to a computer, I would write on paper, fold it up, and staple the spine so that I could open it up like a book. (This reminds me that I would love to try my hand at book binding!) But while I spent a lot of my early years writing, it kind of faded away as I got more busy in late high school and into college.</p>
<p>I’m super proud to say that I actually wrote an <em>entire trilogy</em> when I was in middle-high school. Was it any good? No. Absolutely not. There were about 10 different plots going on at once since I couldn’t decide which I wanted to keep. But regardless, I somehow stumbled my way to the end of a ~150k word journey. And that was one of the last writing projects I had.</p>
<p>But! I’ve always wanted to participate in NaNoWriMo, and what better time than in my senior year of college? I was lucky enough to have a job offer at DataDog lined up post graduation, and to be mostly done with my academic requirements, so I had more time on my hands for the first time in a few years, and, most importantly, I had <em>inspiration.</em></p>
<p>The hardest part about writing is truly getting the story in your head into a fully fleshed out, developed idea. I’ve had many, many story ideas over the years, but they were such one-dimensional ideas – more like a single quote or scene that I wanted to write into reality – that they could barely be considered a wisp of smoke in the grand scheme of things. In comparison, I had slowly been brewing an idea that was more akin to a flame, or even an entire bonfire, in terms of my passion and my motivation for it.</p>
<p>I have a lot to thank to Madeline Miller, the wonderful author of the book <em>The Song of Achilles.</em> It’s a retelling of <em>The Iliad</em> by Homer*,* the story of Achilles and the war against Troy, from the viewpoint of Patroclus, who was Achilles’ close friend (and lover?). I read <em>The Song of Achilles</em> earlier in 2023, and I was absolutely in love with the depth of the characters and the inescapable tragedy in the end. Her writing is so captivating as well, and I’m currently reading another one of her books, <em>Circe</em>.</p>
<p>I decided that I wanted to write something akin to <em>The Song of Achilles</em>, in that it is also a retelling of <em>The Iliad</em> from Patroclus’ perspective, but that’s about where the similarities end. I made Achilles and Patroclus women, because I figured that women would be more enjoyable for me to write as a woman, and I created an entire nation(s) to set the scene in. I created my own gods and a new war to take place. The prophecy is mostly the same, though. The princess who takes Achilles’ place in my novel is doomed to die while fighting her nation’s war.</p>
<p>What’s more, I also decided to pull from more Greek mythology. My story is about women (or at least, it is in it’s rough state right now), and what woman in Greek mythology could I easily take inspiration for? I took an alternate interpretation of the story of Medusa. Many people know Medusa as the evil, snake-haired woman who turns everyone she looks to into stone. She’s cruel, unforgiving, and a monster above all. But, what I wanted to take was her origin story.</p>
<p>Most stories say that she lay with Poseidon in Athena&rsquo;s temple, and was thus punished by Athena to have her hair turned into snakes and to have her gaze turn others into stone. But other interpretations tell a slightly different story. Medusa was a mortal, and she was raped by Poseidon at the temple. Instead of punishing her, Athena gave Medusa her hair and her eyes as a way of protection, to ward off any other men who may try to take advantage of her.</p>
<p>In the end, it’s still a tragedy, for Medusa is still, by most people’s definition, a monster. And she was killed for it. And that is the story of Medusa that I wanted to incorporate into my story.</p>
<p>Currently, it’s been about four months since I started writing my novel, and many more months since I started developing its ideas in my head. It’s still a far way away from finishing, but it’s the most excited I’ve been over a writing project in many, many years. I still get bursts of inspiration and plot ideas when I’m going about my day, and I have a whole list of thoughts that I’m itching to put into writing. I feel that it’s safe to say that my motivation to write has returned after a five year hiatus. Here’s to, I hope, even more years of writing!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
